hey guys we have a castle here
surrounded by a moat and the moat has a
width of 20 meters all the way around
and you happen to have two boards that
are exactly 19 meters long is there a
way to use these two boards to get to
the castle so obviously we can't do it
this way because it's not going to be
long enough to reach but what if we put
it at a 45 degree angle like this and
then put the other board right here on
top of it will this be long enough to
reach well let's zoom in on it and do
some of the math first let's look at how
far is this total diagonal distance we
need to reach and let's call that
distance D this makes an isosceles right
triangle where this side is equal to 20
and this side is equal to 20. so we can
solve 20 squared plus 20 squared equals
D Squared that's 400 plus 400 equals D
Squared which is 800 equals D Squared
and after you square root 800 you get D
is approximately equal to 28.28 let's
keep this here but get rid of everything
else so this whole board is equal to 19
which would mean that the half board
would be half of 19 which is 9.5 this
also makes an isosceles right triangle
where this this side right here is also
9.5 and this is important so let's mark
this 9.5 as red and let's get rid of
this stuff and now let's bring these
boards back well this board is one of
those original 19 foot boards with these
two boards set up like this we can
Traverse a diagonal that is 19 plus 9.5
meters and 19 plus 9.5 is equal to 28.5
well the 28.5 we can cross with our two
boards is greater than the diagonal size
of 28.28 so this method checks out how
exciting